<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>connected-components on Hashnopolis</title>
    <link>http://www.hashnopolis.com/tags/connected-components/</link>
    <description>Recent content in connected-components on Hashnopolis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Hashnopolis</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 20:24:47 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.hashnopolis.com/tags/connected-components/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Number of Islands Ii</title>
      <link>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/number-of-islands-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 20:24:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/number-of-islands-ii/</guid>
      <description>A 2d grid map of m rows and n columns is initially filled with water. We may perform an addLand operation which turns the water at position (row, col) into a land. Given a list of positions to operate, count the number of islands after each addLand operation. An island is surrounded by water and is formed by connecting adjacent lands horizontally or vertically. You may assume all four edges of the grid are all surrounded by water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Routers</title>
      <link>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/critical-routers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:18:54 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/critical-routers/</guid>
      <description>You are given an undirected connected graph. An articulation point (or cut vertex) is defined as a vertex which, when removed along with associated edges, makes the graph disconnected (or more precisely, increases the number of connected components in the graph). The task is to find all articulation points in the given graph.
Input:
The input to the function/method consists of three arguments:
 numNodes, an integer representing the number of nodes in the graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Connections</title>
      <link>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/critical-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 10:01:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/critical-connections/</guid>
      <description>Given an underected connected graph with n nodes labeled 1..n. A bridge (cut edge) is defined as an edge which, when removed, makes the graph disconnected (or more precisely, increases the number of connected components in the graph). Equivalently, an edge is a bridge if and only if it is not contained in any cycle. The task is to find all bridges in the given graph. Output an empty list if there are no bridges.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>