<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>divide-and-conquer on Hashnopolis</title>
    <link>http://www.hashnopolis.com/tags/divide-and-conquer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in divide-and-conquer on Hashnopolis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Hashnopolis</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 23:59:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.hashnopolis.com/tags/divide-and-conquer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Search a 2d Matrix II</title>
      <link>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/2019/04/search-a-2d-matrix-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 23:59:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/2019/04/search-a-2d-matrix-ii/</guid>
      <description>Write an efficient algorithm that searches for a value in an m x n matrix. This matrix has the following properties:
 Integers in each row are sorted in ascending from left to right. Integers in each column are sorted in ascending from top to bottom.  Example: Consider the following matrix: [ [1, 4, 7, 11, 15], [2, 5, 8, 12, 19], [3, 6, 9, 16, 22], [10, 13, 14, 17, 24], [18, 21, 23, 26, 30] ] Given target = 5, return true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House Robber III</title>
      <link>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/2019/02/house-robber-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 20:56:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/2019/02/house-robber-iii/</guid>
      <description>The thief has found himself a new place for his thievery again. There is only one entrance to this area, called the &amp;ldquo;root.&amp;rdquo; Besides the root, each house has one and only one parent house. After a tour, the smart thief realized that &amp;ldquo;all houses in this place forms a binary tree&amp;rdquo;. It will automatically contact the police if two directly-linked houses were broken into on the same night.
Determine the maximum amount of money the thief can rob tonight without alerting the police.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House Robber II</title>
      <link>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/2019/02/house-robber-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 19:39:05 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/2019/02/house-robber-ii/</guid>
      <description>You are a professional robber planning to rob houses along a street. Each house has a certain amount of money stashed. All houses at this place are arranged in a circle. That means the first house is the neighbor of the last one. Meanwhile, adjacent houses have security system connected and it will automatically contact the police if two adjacent houses were broken into on the same night.
Given a list of non-negative integers representing the amount of money of each house, determine the maximum amount of money you can rob tonight without alerting the police.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowest Common Ancestor of a Binary Search Tree</title>
      <link>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/2018/11/lowest-common-ancestor-of-a-binary-search-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 13:23:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/2018/11/lowest-common-ancestor-of-a-binary-search-tree/</guid>
      <description>Given a binary search tree (BST), find the lowest common ancestor (LCA) of two given nodes in the BST.
According to the definition of LCA on Wikipedia: “The lowest common ancestor is defined between two nodes p and q as the lowest node in T that has both p and q as descendants (where we allow a node to be a descendant of itself).”
Given binary search tree: root = [6,2,8,0,4,7,9,null,null,3,5]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowest Common Ancestor of a Binary Tree</title>
      <link>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/2018/11/lowest-common-ancestor-of-a-binary-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 13:18:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/2018/11/lowest-common-ancestor-of-a-binary-tree/</guid>
      <description>Given a binary tree, find the lowest common ancestor (LCA) of two given nodes in the tree.
According to the : “The lowest common ancestor is defined between two nodes p and q as the lowest node in T that has both p and q as descendants (where we allow a node to be a descendant of itself).”
Given the following binary tree: root = [3,5,1,6,2,0,8,null,null,7,4]
 _______3______ / \ ___5__ ___1__  / \ / 6 _2 0 8 / 7 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House Robber</title>
      <link>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/2018/10/house-robber/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 23:45:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hashnopolis.com/post/2018/10/house-robber/</guid>
      <description>You are a professional robber planning to rob houses along a street. Each house has a certain amount of money stashed, the only constraint stopping you from robbing each of them is that adjacent houses have security system connected and it will automatically contact the police if two adjacent houses were broken into on the same night.
Given a list of non-negative integers representing the amount of money of each house, determine the maximum amount of money you can rob tonight without alerting the police.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>